welcome to another installment of the
right chest and redux video series if
you haven't been following along it will
probably be much easier to start at the
beginning since each video builds on
where the previous video left off
and remember to get up to speed on Redux
itself you really can't beat ya diode
videos
paradoxes creator Dan aber muss
when we left off last time we had our
right tag dispatching action having a go
through the reduced her returning in
your state and having that new state
reflected in our tack one of the key
benefits of a system like redux and the
fact that our entire application is
represented by a single state tree that
we have multiple tags communicate with
each other without actually knowing
about each other as long as they're
aware of the store where the state
that's being passed into them they can
act independently and user dispatcher to
get information backup update the state
so we're going to take our existing
example I'm gonna break it down into
multiple tags performance in its own tag
it dispatches and action and we make
sure that our output tag still updates
the title based on that form input so to
get started I'm gonna add a new tags
gonna call it title forum entitled form
had the route eggs tabled a sworn to
keep things simple we gotta go to my
sample output headache and I'm gonna cut
the forum and the associated script tank
leaving only the title and I'm gonna go
back to my title form tag I'm gonna put
that for content and the script tag with
the handler entitle form
gonna go back to index that Jas I'm
gonna have to require to say I have four
sample output had one for our newsletter
form tank and I'm gonna update my column
right time and person Astrix that way at
all now and he's had that on the HTML
file and then I'm going to go into index
HTML I'm gonna horizontal rule just we
have some kind of visual to show us that
this is new output advertiser form tag
into the HTML and now you can go over to
my browser and refresh mostly that are
horizontal rules there and our form is
there but this time it's in its own
take survey get on the browser and type
in this is my new title and I clicked
changed will see that nothing happened
so the problem is our stories
dispatching or action or action is
running through the reduce her at a new
state is being returned but because the
action is happening in a different tag
right isn't actually updating the
default title tag I'm sorry the sample
output eg because it is aware that it
needs to do an update there just to
prove this let's go to indexed at Jas
and I'm gonna had my console back in the
browser and refresh
they've been some new title will see
that our action is still being
dispatched but we need to make sure that
sample output tag nosed update itself so
we're gonna get a sample output tang and
I'm gonna add some script tanks and I
want to access the store that I'm
getting through the options and the
store as we've seen so far hasn't get
state method that allows us to get
access to the state and also has the
dispatch method that allows us to pass
action objects into the reducer and it
has a subscribe method and subscribe
method is how we're gonna notifier tag
that the state has changed and it needs
to be updated so subscribers gonna take
it out of its function and in or
subscribe function we're gonna call
riots this done update and because I'm
using this inside this anonymous
function I need to make sure I call bind
with their song that function or to have
a different scope for this and now that
we have set that up and go back to our
browser
give it another new title
this time everything works now we have
an opportunity to do some refactoring so
we're going to clean up our code a bit
while retaining the exact same
functionality we have current if we look
at the title form tag will see that our
dispatches passing this object literal
as our action object this is water
reducers expecting but there are two
pieces of data and the action object and
only one that is actually derived from
the event handler and our tag that's the
value of the input when the form is
submitted the type property is a string
that is essentially constant value so
we're going to move the creation of this
object into an action creator reaction
Creator will take the title value as an
argument and return this object with
that new title value and place your
order to get that going what we're gonna
do is we're going to add and actions Jas
file in our source directory and that's
going to export a module so put in
module that exports will set that equal
an object literal and I wanna give it a
method called change title and I'm gonna
point change table to a function called
change diaper change sale is going to
take an argument and that's going to be
the new title and that's going to return
our action upset so the first thing our
action object needs are type which is
going to be changed title again using
exactly what we did from within the tag
or just refactoring the sale that's
going to have a data property and that's
going to take the new title value and
pass that along to me I'm going to go
back to my title form tank and I'm gonna
comment this dispatch call cuz I want to
replace it but I want to keep it as a
reference to add a new call to stored at
dispatch and this time he's my action
creator to put the action object and as
dispatches argument in a very do that I
need to get a reference to my actions
object soyuz require actions that Jas
and then inside the dispatch function of
has it actions . change title and change
table takes an argument to represent the
new titles value we can use this start
new title that value
let's go to a browser and refresh and
see if everything still works now that
we've refactored does so I can go into
my changed later function and i cant
delete a comment about Persian and now
we've refactored to use action creators
with redux
thank you for watching hope you found
this video helpful and be sure to keep
an eye out for the next video in the
series